alltrails.com 2017-06-06

# Privacy Policy | AllTrails.com

**Last updated on January 17, 2012.**

 **AllTrails, Inc.** ( _“AllTrails”_ , _“our”_ , _“us”_ or _“we”_ ) provides this Privacy Policy to inform you of our policies and procedures regarding the collection, use and disclosure of personal information we receive from users of [alltrails.com](http://alltrails.com/) (collectively, the _“Site”_ ) and our proprietary and co-branded applications for mobile devices (any and all of the foregoing, the _“Application”_ ). This Privacy Policy applies only to information that you provide to us through the Site and Application. This Privacy Policy may be updated from time to time. We will notify you of any material changes by posting the new Privacy Policy on the Site or via the Application. You are advised to consult this policy regularly for any changes. Unless otherwise defined in this Privacy Policy, terms used in this Privacy Policy have the same meanings as in our AllTrails Terms of Use

As used in this policy, the terms “using” and “processing” information include using cookies on a computer, subjecting the information to statistical or other analysis and using or handling information in any way, including, but not limited to collecting, storing, evaluating, modifying, deleting, using, combining, disclosing and transferring information within our organization or among our affiliates within the United States or internationally.

Information Collection and Use

Our primary goals in collecting information are to provide and improve our Site, Application, services, features and content, to administer your use of the Site and Application (together, the _“Service”_ ) and to enable users to enjoy and easily navigate the Site and Application.

**Personally Identifiable Information.**

  * In the course of using the Service, we may ask you to provide us with, or grant us access to, or permission to obtain, certain personally identifiable information that can be used to contact or identify you (“ _Personal Information_ ”). Personal Information includes, but is not limited to, your name, phone number, pictures of you, your email address, your postal address and your billing information (e.g., credit card number and billing address).

  * In order to access certain features of the Service, you must register to create an account ( _"Account"_ ) and become a _"Member"_. In connection with registration we will collect Personal Information from you. (See “ _Information Sharing and Disclosure: Preferred Partners,_ ” below for a description of the circumstances under which we may share information, which may contain your Personal Information, with our partners). 

  * You may register directly via the Site and Application or by logging into your account with certain third party social networking services ( _“SNS”_ ) via the Site and Application, as described herein. If you decide to register through an SNS, we will extract the Personal Information and other information you have provided to the SNS (such as your “real” name, email address, profile picture and other information you choose to make publicly available via the applicable SNS) from the account you have with the applicable SNS and use that information to create your Account. The specific information that we extract may depend on the privacy settings you have with the SNS. We use your Personal Information mainly to provide the Service, complete your transactions and administer your inquiries. 

  * We also collect the other information that you provide as part of registration and the administration and personalization of your profile webpage (e.g., without limitation, age, zip code (on its own) and individual preferences) ( _“Non-Identifying Information”_ ). For users of the Application, the type of Non-Identifying Information we collect also includes, but is not limited to: (i) mobile device type, device identification code and device properties; (ii) geographical data, including, but not limited to, your country of residence; and (iii) ads you click on within the Application. 

  * Certain Non-Identifying Information would be considered a part of your Personal Information if it were combined with other identifiers (for example, combining your zip code with your street address) in a way that enables you to be identified. But the same pieces of information are considered Non-Identifying Information when they are taken alone or combined only with other non-identifying information (for example, your viewing preferences). We may combine your Personal Information with Non-Identifying Information and aggregate it with information collected from other AllTrails Users (defined below) to attempt to provide you with a better experience, to improve the quality and value of the Service and to analyze and understand how our Site, Application and Service are used. We may also use the combined information without aggregating it to serve you specifically, for instance to deliver a product to you according to your preferences or restrictions. 

  * We also use your Personal Information to contact you with AllTrails newsletters, marketing or promotional materials and other information that may be of interest to you. If you decide at any time that you no longer wish to receive such communications from us, please follow the unsubscribe instructions provided in any of the communications or via the “My Account” section of the Site. (See _“Changing or Deleting Information,”_ below.) 

  * **Promotions.** From time to time we may provide you the opportunity to participate in surveys, contests or sweepstakes (collectively, _“Promotions”_ ) through the Site and Application. If you decide to participate, we will request certain Personal Information from you. Participation in these Promotions is completely voluntary and you have a choice whether or not to disclose this information. We use this information to administer your participation in each Promotion. 

  * **Log Data.** When you visit the Site and Application, whether as a Member or a non-registered user just browsing (any of these, an _“AllTrails User”_ ), our servers automatically record information that your browser sends whenever you visit a website ( _“Log Data”_ ). This Log Data may include information such as your computer’s Internet Protocol ( _“IP”_ ) address, browser type or the webpage you were visiting before you came to our Site and Application, pages of our Site and Application that you visit, the time spent on those pages, information you search for on our Site and Application, access times and dates, and other statistics. We use this information to monitor and analyze use of the Site, Application and Service and for the Site and Application’s technical administration, to increase our Site and Application’s functionality and user-friendliness, and to better tailor our Site and Application to our visitors’ needs. For example, some of this information is collected so that when you visit the Site and Application again, the Site and Application will recognize you and serve advertisements and other information appropriate to your interests. We also use this information to verify that visitors to the Site and Application meet the criteria required to process their requests. 

Cookies & Other Technologies

Like many websites, we use “cookies” to collect information. A cookie is a small data file that we transfer to your computer’s hard disk for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies for two purposes. First, we utilize persistent cookies to save your login information for future logins to the Site and Application. Second, we utilize session ID cookies to enable certain features of the Site and Application, to better understand how you interact with the Site and Application and to monitor aggregate usage by AllTrails Users and web traffic routing on the Site and Application. Unlike persistent cookies, session cookies are deleted from your computer when you log off from the Site, Application and Service and then close your browser. Third party advertisers on the Site and Application may also place or read cookies on your browser. You can instruct your browser, by changing its options, to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from the websites you visit. If you do not accept cookies, however, you may not be able to use all portions of the Site and Application or all functionality of the Service. 

We also use "web beacons," "pixel tags," "clear GIFs" or similar means (individually or collectively _"Web Beacons"_ ) on our Site and Application. A Web Beacon is an electronic image, often a single pixel, embedded on web pages. Web Beacons are ordinarily not visible to users. Web Beacons allow us to count the number of users who have visited certain pages of the Site and Application to deliver branded services and to generate statistics about how our Site and Application are used. 

Phishing

Identity theft and the practice currently known as “phishing” are of great concern to AllTrails. Safeguarding information to help protect you from identity theft is a top priority. We do not and will not, at any time, request your credit card information, login information, or national identification numbers in a non-secure or unsolicited e-mail or telephone communication. For more information about phishing, visit the Federal Trade Commission’s website. 

Inviting a Friend to Use AllTrails

As part of the Service, Members may invite non-registered users to use the Service through use of their Accounts. Where a Member selects the option of adding one or more email addresses to an online form, the message such Member creates in the corresponding template will be sent from AllTrails to those email addresses on the Member’s behalf. These email addresses will be used only for the purpose of sending the communication to the addressee. 

Information Sharing and Disclosure

**AllTrails Members.** We will display your Personal Information in your profile page and elsewhere on the Site and via our Service according to the preferences you set in your Account. For example, AllTrails Users will see your profile picture, name, location (city and state), the date you first registered via the Service, your Member status and your favorite activities. AllTrails Users will also see information related to your activities on the Site and Application, including, but not limited to, photos you upload, trails you create or complete, reviews of trails you post and individuals you add as friends and follow via the Service. If you would like to make the information in your profile private (i.e., not publicly viewable via the Site and Application), you may do so via the “My Profile” section of the Site and Application. Providing your Personal Information is voluntary and should correlate with the degree of interaction you want to have with others. For further information regarding “Submissions” see the AllTrails Terms of Use. 

**Preferred Partners.** We may share the information you provide during registration (e.g., your username, name, email address and zip code) (“Specific Shared Data”) with certain of our partners (“Preferred Partners”) for those parties to use such Specific Shared Data to provide you with information and marketing materials about their own applications, products and services and to further enhance your use of our Service. For example, such data sharing may occur when you use an Application that is co-branded by AllTrails and one or more of our Preferred Partners. At the time of registration to use the Service, you may have the option to opt out of our sharing Specific Shared Data, with the applicable Preferred Partner. We only share Specific Shared Data with our Preferred Partners pursuant to an agreement under which the Preferred Partner is obligated to maintain and use the Specific Shared Data it receives solely for the purposes for which it was provided to the partner or in compliance with applicable law. Notwithstanding the foregoing, in the event that the Preferred Partner’s privacy policy is surfaced to you in connection with the registration process, the Preferred Partner’s privacy policy will also apply to the use of your Specific Shared Data by the Preferred Partner. 

**SNSs.** The Service gives you the option to share information contained in your Account with certain SNSs (including but not limited to Twitter and Facebook). AllTrails will not share your Account information, which may contain your Personal Identifiable Information, with such SNSs unless you expressly authorize such disclosure. 

**Facebook Connect.** Our Site and Application allow users to create an Account and login to the Site and Application using their Facebook account credentials through Facebook Connect. By using Facebook Connect, you are allowing AllTrails to access your Facebook account information. If you are not currently registered as a Member and you click on "Sign in Using Facebook," you will first be asked to enter your Facebook credentials and then be given the option to register and join AllTrails. We give Members the option to disable Facebook Connect at any time by accessing your Facebook account and disconnecting access to the Site, Application and Service. 

**Aggregate Information and Non-Identifying Information.** We may share aggregated information that includes your Personal Information, Non-Identifying Information and Log Data with third parties for industry analysis and demographic profiling and to deliver targeted advertising about other products and services. 

**Service Providers.** We may employ third party companies and individuals to facilitate our Service, to provide the Service on our behalf, to perform Site-related services (e.g., without limitation, maintenance services, database management, payment processing, web analytics and improvement of the Site and Application’s features) or to assist us in analyzing how our Site, Application and Service are used. These third parties have access to your Personal Information only to perform these tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose. 

**Compliance with Laws and Law Enforcement.** AllTrails cooperates with government and law enforcement officials and private parties to enforce and comply with the law. We will disclose any information about you to government or law enforcement officials or private parties as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate to respond to claims and legal process (including but not limited to subpoenas), to protect the property and rights of AllTrails or a third party, to protect the safety of the public or any person, or to prevent or stop activity we may consider to be, or to pose a risk of being, illegal, unethical or legally actionable activity. 

**Business Transfers.** AllTrails may sell, transfer or otherwise share some or all of its assets, including your Personal Information, in connection with a merger, acquisition, reorganization or sale of assets or in the event of bankruptcy 

YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS:

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits customers of AllTrails who are California residents to request certain information regarding its disclosure of Personal Information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an e-mail to [privacy_at_alltrails_dot_com](mailto:privacy@alltrails.com) or write us: AllTrails, Inc., 111 Pine Street, Suite 1605, San Francisco, California 94111. 

Changing or Deleting Your Information

All Members may review, update, correct or delete the Personal Information in their Account by contacting us or via the “My Profile” section of the Site and Application. If you completely delete all such information, then your Account may become deactivated. If you would like us to delete your Account in our system, please contact us at [privacy_at_alltrails_dot_com](mailto:privacy@alltrails.com) with a request that we delete your Personal Information from our database. We will use commercially reasonable efforts to honor your request. We may retain an archived copy of your records as required by law or for legitimate business purposes 

Security

AllTrails is very concerned with safeguarding your information. We employ reasonable physical, technological, and administrative security measures and attempt to ensure they are applicable under the circumstances. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. 

We will make any legally required disclosures of any breach of the security, confidentiality, or integrity of your unencrypted electronically stored “personal data” (as defined in applicable state statutes on security breach notification) to you via email or conspicuous posting on the Site or via the Application in the most expedient time possible and without unreasonable delay, insofar as consistent with (i) the legitimate needs of law enforcement or (ii) any measures necessary to determine the scope of the breach and restore the reasonable integrity of the data system. 

International Transfer

Your information may be transferred to — and maintained on — computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the privacy laws may not be as protective as those in your jurisdiction. If you are located outside the United States and choose to provide information to us, AllTrails transfers Personal Information to the United States and processes it there. Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer. 

Links to Other Sites or Applications

Our Site and Application may contain links to other websites or applications, e.g.:

  * Your Account may be linked to your SNS account.

  * There may be advertisements served to you within the Site and Application. 

  * You may be brought to the website of our third party payment processors.

If you click on another third party link, you will be directed to that third party’s website or application. The fact that we link to a website or application is not an endorsement, authorization or representation of our affiliation with that third party, nor is it an endorsement of their privacy or information security policies or practices. We do not exercise control over third party websites or applications. These other websites or applications may place their own cookies or other files on your computer, collect data or solicit personal information from you. Other websites follow different rules regarding the use or disclosure of the personal information you submit to them. We encourage you to read the privacy policies or statements of the other websites you visit. 

Our Policy Toward Children

The Site and Application are not directed to persons under 13. We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13. If a parent or guardian becomes aware that his or her child has provided us with Personal Information without their consent, he or she should contact us at [privacy_at_alltrails_dot_com](mailto:privacy@alltrails.com). If we become aware that a child under 13 has provided us with Personal Information, we will delete such information from our files. 

Contacting Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at [privacy_at_alltrails_dot_com](mailto:privacy@alltrails.com) or at: 

AllTrails, Inc. 111 Pine Street, Suite 1605 San Francisco, CA 94111
